Shannon Thouvenin

3437 Montford Rd S, Westerville, OH 43081 (614) 843-8680 / Shannon.Thouvenin@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Management • Customer Relations • Front-End Solutions

A highly motivated and client focused Freelance Web Developer with strong HTML, CSS and JavaScript experience and substantial success in delivering novel website solutions for a diverse clientele. Maintains attention to detail, demonstrates strong knowledge of programming languages and debugging tools, and stays abreast of emerging technologies. Uses artistry and craftsmanship to translate customer needs into technical requirements, applies an analytical approach to solving problems, and cultivates trusted working relationships. Collaborates effectively in team settings, communicates concisely at all levels, and excels in fast-paced, team-oriented and creative environments. Committed to results that enhance the customer experience.

OBJECTIVE

Currently seeking a challenging new Customer Relations Position that will fully utilize the existing knowledge and experience and provide opportunities for further personal and professional development.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Operational Leadership
- Responsive Design
- Object-Oriented Design
- Strategy Development
- Associate retention
- Website & ETL Development
- Client Engagement & Presentations
- Prospecting & Relationship Building
- Customer Relationship Management
- Team Management & Development
- Front-End Development
- Project Management
- Relational Database Queries
- Warehouse Operations
- Process Optimization

TECHNOLOGIES

Programming: JavaScript, Ruby, Python, SQL, jQuery, AngularJS, **Microsoft Office Suite:** Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, and Outlook

Other: CSS, HTML, Twitter-Bootstrap, Git Control Version, Rspec, Chrome Developer Tools, Microsoft Visual Studio,

Google Analytics, SAP

CAREER SUMMARY

Freelance Web Development, Westerville, OH (Dec 2016 - Present)

Independent Web Developer & JavaScript Programmer

- Sourcing and identifying prospective clients for the development of new websites or enhancements to existing sites
 and preparing wireframe sketches for presentation to clients.
- Using knowledge of web-based development to engage effectively with clients and customers by phone and email.
- Ensuring that the created sites are seamless across all devices and using Chrome Developer tools for debugging
- Using Git Control Version frequently to commit changes to GitHub.

UPS, Columbus, OH (February 2018 - Present)

Safety Supervisor (Logistics Manager)

- Oversees compliance and safety of 240 employees
- Ensures safety standards and procedures are followed per protocol.
- Accountable for being audit ready at all times
- Handles injury reporting and procedures.

HD Supply, Groveport, OH (Oct 2015 - Mar 2017)

Lead Warehouse Associate (Management)

- Led a team of between 18 and 20 individuals, held the team accountable for accurate picking and production standards, and provided coaching opportunities.
- Managed out of product merchandise and ensured the safe transportation of product.
- Maintained accurate records of batches and items needing new locations.
- Adjusted and pulled merchandise from other DCs in order to meet customer needs, developed excellent knowledge

- of SAP functions, and used SAP to adjust customer orders.
- Researched Overages and Shortages based on records from the previous day.
- Streamlined processes to enhance efficiency, which included the layout of the dock and conveyors.

PetSmart, Dublin, Polaris, Columbus, and Massillon OH May 2007 - Oct 2015)

Merchandise & Inventory Leader (Receiving Manager) Polaris, Columbus, OH (May 2014 - Oct 2015)

- Drove store revenue and profitability, used SAP to manage inventory, and placed orders for product in line with increasing demand.
- Oversaw up to 20 employees at any given time, managed the cleanliness and organization of the shelves, and ensured that shelves were filled with product.
- Received freight 3 days a week, managed a team to unload freight, and tracked the manifest report.

Operations Manager (LIT) Dublin, OH (Jan 2014 - May 2014)

- Oversaw store operations and streamlined processes in order to boost efficiency and cut costs.
- Supervised departmental Managers, maintained a comprehensive understanding of operations in all departments, and enforced Company policies and procedures.
- Carried responsibility for up to 60 employees, ensured the achievement of key performance indicators (KPIs), and dealt with disciplinary action and opportunities.
- Interviewed and hired new employees and provided training and certification for all Associates.
- Managed payroll and prepared the schedule.
- Ensured the security of client information and resolved challenging and sensitive customer issues.

Support Manager (Customer Engagement Leader) Easton - Columbus, OH (May 2012 - May 2014)

- Ensured that Cashiers completed comprehensive training and prepared all deposits.
- Maintained a high level of team energy and enthusiasm and resolved complex customer issues.
- Served as the only On-Site Manager in the evenings.

Support Manager (Customer Engagement Leader) Easton - Columbus, OH (May 2007 - May 2012)

- Maintained a strong record of achievement through roles of increasing responsibility for this supplier of pet solutions.
- Recognized repeatedly for outstanding team and customer service leadership through the growth of the Company.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Benefit Series

Volunteer

- Assisted with the development of websites to increase awareness to enable photographers to come together and help other photographers in the community.
- Contributed to the creation of a website and the launch of a benefit for a photographer that was about to lose her home, due to a lengthy illness and increasing medical bills.
- Provided assistance to the owner of Properazzi, which provided vintage props and locations for photographers.
- Built a site and led a project to raise funds to help her save her home following the passing of her husband.

EDUCATION

Thomas Edison State University, Trenton, New Jersey

BS/BA Computer Information Systems, Currently Attending

Ohio State University. Columbus, OH, 2013

Master of Music, 3.681 GPA

Mount Union College, Alliance, OH, 2010

Bachelor of Music with Honors, 3.700 GPA

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Coding & Programming

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Bootstrap and AngularJS, Coursera
- Intermediate to Advanced HTML and CSS, Girl Develop, Columbus, OH

Front-End Development (Coursera)

- University of Michigan, Ann Arbor MI
- Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD
- Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong